FARNAZ TOWHIDI FRONT-END ENGINEER

Toronto, Ontario, (506) 897-2353, farnaz.towhidi@gmail.com github.com/FarnazTowhidi, farnaztowhidi.com

HIGHLIGHTS

Front-stack developer with years of experience in designing and developing user interface, testing, debugging, implementing components in amazing companies like IBM, Canadian Institute of Cyber Security and Biossentials. I always feel passionate about increasing the limits to academic knowledge thus my PHD and increasing the knowledge in General Assembly of Toronto.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Language, Frameworks, and Libraries: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, DOM, Bootstrap, React.js, Express,js, Node.js, Python, Django, Jira, Jenkins, TestRail, Eclipse, Selenium
- Database and DB Management Tools: MongoDB, SQL, mongoDB, Mongoose
- **Methodologies:** Object Oriented Programing, MVC pattern, Responsive Design, Oath Authentication, User stories, Wire framing, REST APIs, Deploy GitHub, Heroku, Git and Git Hub, Middleware, Mern Infrastructure, Agile Scrum

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

2021 - 2022

Iranian Iron & Steel Institute of Education (Remote), Tehran, Iran

- Implemented a website for workshops on Metallurgical and Materials engineering
- HTML, CSS, ASP Classic

Frontend Developer

2019

Canadian Institute of Cybersecurity, Fredericton, New Brunswick

- Designed and built website for International Conference on Privacy, Security and Trust, including information on events, workshops, organizers.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, ASP Classic

Frontend Developer

2009 - 2014

Biossentials, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Worked closely with a designer to create new comprehensive layout
- Coded company website from ground up based on new graphic design, along with SEO audits that considered on page and off-page
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, ASP Classic, SEO

Full Stack Developer

2005 - 2008

Maadiran, Tehran, Iran

 Designed and modified dynamic web site for products automation, manufacturing, and after-sales support as a part of team of 4

- Analyzed user's needs and converted them to create right solutions, such as selecting products based on user's requirement
- Technologies used: Asp dot net, Microsoft SQL server, HTML, CSS

Full Stack Developer

2002 - 2005

Parsportfolio, Tehran, Iran

- Part of a team of 7 to build stock trading website with monthly traffic of over
 1 million visitors
- Contributed to coding applications for educational and salary portal using OOP
- Assisted in designing a training CD, including a hands-on guide for investing and trading stocks
- Technologies used: HTML, Asp dot net, Microsoft visual studio, Microsoft SQL server

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance (Contract)

2020

IBM, Fredericton, New Brunswick

- Part of security intelligence team of 10 working on QRadar admin
- Knowledge on QRadar log and network activity and reports
- Created and edited automated test cases, manual, automation and regression testing
- Technologies used: Selenium, QRadar, Eclipse, Test Rail, Git, Git Hub

PROJECTS

McDonald's Application

Github

- DRY REST API for fully-functional styled McDonald's inventory application
- Technologies used: Express/Node and MongoDB, Python

Chatterbox

Github

- Mern stack application, a responsive single page application
- Uploader with the use of AWS S3 buckets and the npm package, "aws-sdk"
- Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React, Socket.io, Amazon Web Services

Track Fit

<u>Github</u>

- Full crud application, for recording the user's daily fitness log
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Python, Django, PostreSQL

War Card Game

<u>Github</u>

- The browser base game, using application state, manipulating DOM and Includes shuffling and win/loss logic
- Technologies used: Html, CSS and JavaScript, Deploy on github

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive, General Assembly, (GPA 3.98 of 4)

2022

PHD of Computer Science, UTM University, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Master of Information Security, UTM University, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, (GPA 3.65 of 4)